

E-mail: tkelarabi@gmail.com Dr. Tarek Elarabi

Phone: +1(337) 326-1434

Objective

I have a multifaceted academic career with 8+ years of teaching graduate and undergraduate students and 7+years track record of research and development in Image and Video Processing. I am expert in designing, optimizing, testing, validating, and prototyping Video Codec systems with emphasize on the H.264/AVC and H.265/HEVC standard. I am looking for a challenging position that utilizes my knowledge, helps me to grow my teaching skills and research experiences

Education & Professional Training

■ PhD in Computer Engineering. (GPA: 4.0/4.0)

(Dec 2012)

The Center for Advanced Computer Studies (CACS), Lafayette, LA USA.

University of Louisiana at Lafayette (ULL).

Dissertation Title: "Real-Time Heterogeneous Video Transcoding for Mobile Applications".

Master of Science in Computer Engineering. (GPA: 4.0/4.0)

(May 2010)

The Center for Advanced Computer Studies (CACS), Lafayette, LA USA.

University of Louisiana at Lafayette (ULL).

Bachelor of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering. (GPA: 4.0/4.0)

(Dec 2008)

 $\label{lem:continuous} \mbox{Arab Academy for Science, Technology and Maritime Transport (AAST)}.$

College Of Engineering and Technology, Alexandria, ARE.

- Technology Certification:
 - Cisco CCNA Certified. (CSCO11790900)
 Switches & Routers, VoIP and Video
 - Microsoft Certified IT Professional (MCITP)
 - Microsoft IT Professional:
 - Developer for Microsoft Dynamics NAV2009. [D677-6241]
 - Installation & Configuration for Microsoft Dynamics NAV2009. [D634-5147]

Work Experiences

• California State University-Fresno August 2014 – Present
Assistant Professor at Electrical and Computer Department [tenure-track]

• Intel Mask Operation Data Center Infrastructure Senior Engineer July 2013 – July 2015 Intel Corporation

Intel Mask Operation (IMO –SC2) Santa Clara, CA USA

Associate Faculty
 December 2013 – Present

West Valley Mission Collage, Santa Clara, CA

Research Associate
 December 2012 – Present

The Center for Advanced Computer Studies (CACS)

University of Louisiana at Lafayette (ULL), Lafayette LA

• IT Professional/ ERP Technical Instructor & Consultant September 2011 – August 2014

ALLCOM, Inc

Lecturer/ Academic Graduate Advisor
 August 2009 – December 2012

The Center for Advanced Computer Studies (CACS)

University of Louisiana at Lafayette (ULL); Lafayette LA USA

RF Design Engineer (Intern)
 May 2011 – August 2011

Forward Link, A Division of CBM of America, Inc

Graduate Teacher Assistant (GTA)
 February 2008 - May2009 College

of Computer Science, Academy for Science & Technology; AAST



E-mail: tkelarabi@gmail.com Dr. Tarek Elarabi

Phone: +1(337) 326-1434

Teaching Experience:

- Graduate Courses Taught
 - High Performance Computer Architecture [ECE274]
 - Advanced Computer Networking [ECE246] (New Course I developed and taught Spring 2015)
 - Advanced Computer Architecture [ECE174G]
- Undergraduate Courses Taught
 - Digital Logic Design [ECE85]
 - Digital Logic Design Laboratory [ECE85L]
 - Switching Theory and Logical Design [ECE106]
 - Computer Organization [ECE115]
 - Microprocessor Arch and Programming [ECE 118]
 - Microcontroller Laboratory [ECE 120L]
 - Advanced Computer Architecture [ECE174]
 - Mobile Applications Lab [ECE122L] (New Course I developed and taught Fall 2015)
 - o Engineering Computations Using C [ECE70]
 - Mobile Apps Programming iPhone [CISO60-Online] (New Course I developed and taught since Fall 2014)
 - Linux Essentials I [CIS045]

Selective Publications

Journals:

- T. Elarabi, Randa Ayoubi, Hanan Mahmud and M. Bayoumi,
 - "Efficient 45nm ASIC Architecture for Full-Search Free Intra Prediction for Real-Time H.264/AVC Decoder", Springer Journal, SI: SiPS2012.
- J. McNeely, Y. Ismail, T. Elarabi and M. Bayoumi,
 - " 'Voodoo' Error Prediction System for Scalable Video Coding ", Hindawi Publishing Corporation, 2011.

Conferences:

- Tarek Elarabi,
 - "Effectiveness of the Hybrid F2F/Online Model for Junior and Senior Engineering Courses", 2016 American Society for Engineering Education Pacific Southwest Conference ASEE-PSW
- Tarek Elarabi, Vishal Deep, Chashamdeep Rai
 - "Optimal Hardware Design of State-of-Art ZigBee Transmitter for IoT Wireless Devices", IEEE International Symposium on Signal Processing and Information Technology, ISSPIT- 2015
- Tarek Elarabi, Abhijit Suprem
 - "Orientation and Displacement Detection for Smartphone-Device Based Inertial Measurement Units", IEEE International Symposium on Signal Processing and Information Technology, ISSPIT- 2015
- T. Elarabi, A. Sammoud and M. Bayoumi
 - "Hybrid Wavelet/ DCT INTRA prediction For H.264/AVC Codec", IEEE ChinaSIP July 2014, Xi'an China.
- T. Elarabi and M. Bayoumi
 - "Full-Search Free Intra Prediction Algorithm for Real-Time H.264/AVC Decoder",
 - Signal Processing, Image Processing and Pattern Recognition, SIP2012 Jeju, Korea.
- T. Elarabi, R. Ayoubi, H. Mahmud and M. Bayoumi,
 - "Hardware Architecture For Fast Intra Mode and Direction Prediction in Real-Time MPEG-2 to H.264/AVC Transcoder", IEEE WoWMoM 2012 /VidEv, San Francesco CA [Acceptance Rate %18].
- T. Elarabi, H. Mahmoud, M. Bayoumi,
 - "High Speed Intra Mode And Direction Prediction for MPEG-2 TO H.264/AVC Real-Time Transcoder", IEEE Workshop on Signal Processing Systems, SiPS 2011, Beirut Lebanon.



E-mail: tkelarabi@gmail.com Dr. Tarek Elarabi

Phone: +1(337) 326-1434

Books:

T. Elarabi, A. Abdelgawad and M. Bayoumi,

"High-Throughput MPEG-2 to H.264/AVC Transcoding for Real-Time Video Applications". (Springer) Spring 2014

T. Elarabi and M. Bayoumi,

"Real-Time Heterogeneous Video Transcoding for Mobile Applications". (Ph.D. Dissertation)

■ T. Elarabi and S. Youssef,

"Wavelet Transformation for Image Compression and Information Hiding". (S. G. Thesis)

Research Interests

- Video Processing: Heterogeneous Video Transcoding, H.264/AVC, HEVC, Scalable Video for IoT applications.
- ▲ Image Processing: Image Compression & Image Retrieval.
- △ Computer Architecture: FPGA for IoT devices, VLSI Low Power Design & ASIC Implementations.
- ▲ Networking: Cross-layer Designs, Congestion Control, Resource Management, Fog Computing & IoT applications.
- A Organic Computing: Biological Inspired Systems for Circuit Level Designs.
- △ Data Storage and Data replication technologies: Asynchronous secured data replication.

Selective projects

\blacktriangle	PoC for Cloud Kiosk Project with California Development & Product Licensing	(Fall 2015)	
\blacktriangle	FPGA based Quad-copter (CSU-Fresno)	(Spring 2015)	
\blacktriangle	MySQL Hi-Availability cluster (Intel)	(Spring 2014)	
\blacktriangle	WAN Latency Linux Based Simulator (Intel)	(Fall 2013)	
\blacktriangle	EMC ² Data Replication Solution for Data Center (Intel)	(Fall 2013)	
\blacktriangle	PBX in a Flash/ FreePBX VoIP Phone System For Allcom, Inc	(Spring/ Fall 2013)	
\blacktriangle	Microsoft ERP NAV 2009 Deployment for Oil Center Research International, Inc	(Fall 2012)	
\blacktriangle	Design and Develop iPhone App for Oil Center Research International, Inc	(Spring 2012)	
\blacktriangle	45 nm ASIC implementation for a Full-Search Free Intra Prediction for H264/AVC Decoder		
	(Simulated using C++ and HW implemented using VHDL and synthesizing Cadence tools).	(Spring 2012)	
\blacktriangle	RF Reader Application for Android mobile devices for on site RF signal strength recording.	(Summer 2011)	
\blacktriangle	Wear Leveling Controller for flash memory array to overcome the flash endurance problem.		
	(Simulated using C++ and HW implemented using Verilog and synthesizing Cadence tools).	(Spring 2011)	
\blacktriangle	MPEG-2 to H.264/AVC Transcoder for real-time applications.		
	(Simulated using C++ and HW implemented using VHDL and synthesizing Cadence tools).	(2011/2012)	
\blacktriangle	Multiphase Digital Ultra-wide-band Transmitter optimized for energy-efficiency.		
	(HW implementation using VHDL, Verilog and synthesizing Cadence tools).	(Full 2010)	
\forall	Client Based Price Monitoring System. (Implemented using JAVA and HTML).	(Spring 2010)	

Professional Development, Organization & Awards

- Academic Senator of the ECE department at CSU- Fresno senate
- ▲ CSU- Fresno DISCOVERe Faculty Fellow
- A CSU- Fresno eScholars Faculty Fellow
- ▲ ASEE Faculty Active Member
- ▲ IEEE Faculty Active Member
- ▲ Member and Web Master for IEEE Computer Society Chapter at ULL
- ▲ Member of the honor society PHI KAPPA PHI
- Member of the technical program committee TPC of MIC-SigProc International Conference
- △ Organizing Member and Web Master in the UCSWSN Conference
- Organizing Member and Web Master in the IEEE SiPS Conference
- Awarded Certificate of Achievement for Academic Excellent by UL Lafayette, May 2012
- A Recognized as Honor Student [2010, 2011 and 2012] by the University of Louisiana at Lafayette
- Awarded the University of Louisiana at Lafayette Assistantship [2009 2012]
- Awarded the Academy for Science & Technology Substantial Student Scholarship [2004 2008]
- Awarded The Academy for Science & Technology Distinguished Students' Award [2004 -2008]